Finding Aid for the Katherine Philips Edson Papers LSC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
Katherine Philips Edson papers
1909-1934
UCLA Library Special Collections
Edson, Katherine Philips
LSC.0235
1 unknown (4 oversize boxes)
Katherine Philips (1870-1933) was a member of the Friday Morning Club in Los Angeles (1908-11), worked on the gubernatorial campaign of Hiram Johnson, was appointed to the California Industrial Welfare Commission, became a member of the State Republican Party (1916-20) and later, a member of the Republican National Committee (1920). The collection consists of correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, and memorabilia concerning Katherine Philip Edson's involvement with women in industry, minimum wage laws, women's suffrage, dairy laws, the Progressive and Republican parties, and the Conference on the Limitation of Armament.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Katherine Edson Mershon, 1945.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9912179213606533
Biography
Katherine Philips was born in 1870; married Charles Farwell Edson and moved to Antelope Valley, California; moved to Los Angeles, 1899; member and later vice president (1908-11) of the Friday Morning Club, Los Angeles, organizing campaigns for pure milk examinations and women's suffrage; association with Progressive Party politics brought her to work on gubernatorial campaign of Hiram Johnson; member, Progressive Party State Central Committee, 1912-16; appointed, California Industrial Welfare Commission, helping to pass state minimum wage and hour laws, 1913; member, executive committee, State Republican Party, 1916-20; member, Republican National Committee, 1920; appointed, American Advisory Board at the Conference on the Limitation of Armaments in Washington, D.C., 1921; headed California Division of Industrial Welfare, 1927-31; died in 1933.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, and memorabilia concerning Katherine Philip Edson's involvement with women in industry, minimum wage laws, women's suffrage, dairy laws, the Progressive and Republican parties, and the Conference on the Limitation of Armament. Includes correspondence from Hiram W. Johnson.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence.
Papers.
Photographs and drawings.
Certificates of appointment.
Scrapbooks.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Katherine Philips Edson Papers (4 items).
Index
Abbott, Grace
Acheson, Dean G.
Miscellaneous: Box 6/folder 7.
Adams, Annette A.
Letters from: Box 2/folder 13
References: Box 3/folder 3.
Adams, John T.
Letters to: Box 1/folder 14
Letters from: Box 3/folder 4
References:
Addams, Jane
References: Box 2/folders 5,9.
Allen, James M.
References: Box 3/folder 12 (Author of Bill).
American Federation of Labor and California Federation of Labor
Anderson, James A.
Letters to: Box 1/folder 11
Letters from: Box 3/folder 3.
Anderson, Mary
Letters to:
Letters from:
References:
Andrews, John B.
Letters to: Box 1/folders 10,12,17
Letters from: Box 3/folders 1,7,9
References: Box 1/folder 10
Miscellaneous: Box 8.
Angelotti, Frank M.
Letters to: Box 1/folder 11
Letters from: Box 3/folder 3.
Anti-Vivisection See--Vivisection.
Athearn, Fred G.
References: Box 3/folders 13,14.
Australia Box 3/folder 8.
Avery, Russ
Letters to: Box 1/folder 2
Letters from: Box 1/folder 2
References: Box 1/folder 4.
Baker, Newton D.
Letters from: Box 2/folder 12
References: Box 2/folder 11.
Baldwin, Louise G.
Letters to: Box 3/folders 12-14
Letters from: Box 3/folders 11-14
Miscellaneous: Box 6/folder 6.
Bancroft, Mrs. Philip
References: Box 1/folder 2.
Bell, George L.
Letters to: Box 1/folder 6
Letters from:
References: Box 1/folder 6.
Bell, Theodore
References:
Benjamin, Raymond
Letters to: Box 1/folders 8-10
Letters from: Box 2/folders 10,13,16
References: Box 1/folders 8,9.
Bertola, Dr. Mariana
Letters to: Box 1/folder 16
References: Box 1/folder 16.
Better America Federation
Beveridge, Albert J.
Letters to: Box 1/folder 11
References: Box 2/folder 13.
Bird, Anna Child (Mrs. Charles Sumner)
References:
Boland, F. Eldred
Letters from: Box 3/folder 2.
Bonnheim, Albert
References:
Booth, Willis H.
References:
Miscellaneous: Box 5/folder 4.
Borah, William E.
References:
Boulder Dam See--Hoover Dam.
Boynton, Albert E.
Brainerd, Chauncey
Brandeis, Louis
Breed, Arthur H.
Briand, Aristide
Briggs, Dr. Arthur H.
Brooks, John G.
Broughton, Esto
Brown, Adelaide, M.D.
Bulla, Robert N.
Burdette, Clara B.
Bush, David F.
Butler, Nicolas Murray
Cabaniss, George H.
California. Immigration and Housing Commission
California. Industrial Accident Commission
California. Industrial Welfare Commission
California Civic League Box 3/folder 2.
California Conference of Social Agencies
California Economic Research Council Box 5/folder 9.
California Federation of Labor See--American Federation of Labor
California Federation of Women's Clubs
Caminetti, Anthony Box 1/folder 5.
Canning and Preserving--Laws and Legislation--California
Carnahan, Herschel L.
Carroll, Mollie Ray
Cartwright, George W.
Catt, Carrie Chapman
Chandler, Harry
Child Labor
China
Christman, Elisabeth
Cole, Olive C.
Commons, John R.
Commonwealth Club
Conference on the Limitation of Armament, Washington, D.C., 1921-22
Coolidge, Calvin
Coolidge, Mary R.
Councils of Defense
Cox, James M.
Craig, Gavin W.
Crail, Joel S.
Creel, George
Crocker, William H.
Cullinan, Eustace
Curtis, Charles G.
Daniels, G.B.
Darrow, Clarence
Daugherty, Harry M.
Daughters of the American Revolution Box 1/folders 14,19.
Davis, James J.
Dawes, Charles G.
Democratic Party
Dempster, Charles W.
Depression
Deutsch, Monroe
Devlin, Frank R.
Dewson, Mary W.
Dickson, Edward A.
Disarmament
De Young, Meichel H.
Dobyns, Fletcher
Dohrmann, A.B.C.
Dover, Elmer
Doyle, Marion Wade
Dreter, Mary E.
Duval, Walter H.
Earl, Edwin T.
Earl, Guy C.
Edson, Charles F.
Edson Family
Elections--California
Elections--U.S.
Electric Power Production See--Water Resources Development.
Eliel, Harriet J.
Eliel, Paul
Ellis Mrs. Overton G.
Emigration and Immigration--U.S.
Employment of Women See--Woman--Employment.
Equal Rights Amendment, Proposed
Eshleman, John M.
European War, 1914-1918
Filene, Edward A.
Fischer, Louis
Fisher, Irving
Flint, Frank P.
References: Box 1/folder 13.
Foltz, Clara Shortridge
Foreign Loans Box 3/folders 1,11.
Foreign Relations See--U.S.--Foreign Relations.
France
Frankfurter, Felix
U.S. Federal Commission On Industrial Relations--1914-1917 Box 2/folders 5,6,8,10,12 (?).
Fredericks, John D.
French, Will J.
Freund, Ernst
Fries, Amos
Gainer, Helen See--Helen Gainer Minimum Wage Case.
Gallagher, andrew J.
Garfield, James A.
Gavit, John
Germany
Gibson, Mary S.
Gompers, Samuel
Gooding, Frank R.
Green, William
Griffin, Frank
Guggenheim, Florence S. (Mrs. Daniel)
Guggenheim, Harry.
Haldeman, Harry M.
Hale, Marshal
Hamilton, Pop
Hard, William
Harding, Florence Kling
Harding, Warren G.
Harris, Morris B.
Harrison, Maurice E.
Harron, Marion J.
Haskins, L.A.
Hayes, Jay O.
Haynes, Dora (Mrs. John R.)
Haynes, John Randolph, M.D.
Hays, Ray W.
Hays, Will H.
Hearst, William Randolph
Helen Gainer Minimum Wage Case
Heney, Francis J.
Herrick, Elinor M.
Hichborn, Franklin
Hicks, Nettie Hayden
Hillman, Sidney
Holcombe, Arthur N.
Holmes, Oliver Wendell
Hoover, Herbert
Hoover, Lou Henry (Mrs. Herbert)
Hoover Dam
Hornblower, William B.
Hotchkiss, Willard E.
Hours of Labor
Howe, Louis Mchenry
Hudson, Manley O.
Hughes, Charles Evans
Hunter, Robert
Ickes, Harold L.
Ihlder, John
Immigration See--Emigration and Immigration--U.S.
India Box 3/folder 2.
Indians, Treatment of Box 5/folder 8.
Industrial Welfare Commission See--California. Industrial Welfare Commission.
Ingels, Russel R.
Insurance, Unemployment
International Courts See--World Court.
Industrial Workers of the World
Irish, John P.
Italy Box 3/folder 5.
Jackson, Grant
James, William P.
Japan
Japanese In California
Johnson, Ethel Mclean
Johnson, Hiram W.
Johnson, Hugh S.
Jones, Herbert C.
Kahn, Florence Prag (Mrs. Julius)
Kahn, Julius
Keesling, Francis V.
Keetch, Arthur
Kelley, Florence
Kellogg, Frederick W.
Kellor, Frances A.
Kenney, Elizabeth
Kent, William
Kerensky
Keynes, John Maynard
Kinney, Mabel E.
Knowland, Joseph R.
Knox, Philander C.
Koster, Frederick J.
Koverman, Ida R.
Labor and Labor Unions
La Follette, Robert
Lamar, Joseph R.
Langdon, William Henry
Laughlin, Gail
Laurie, Annie (Winifred S. Bonfils)
Lawler, Oscar
League For Women's Service
League of Nations
League of Women Voters
Letts, Arthur
Lewis, William Draper
Lippincott, Joseph B.
Lippman, Walter
Lissner, Meyer
Lloyd George, David
Lodge, Henry Cabot, Sr.
Louis, Henry W.
Lubin, Isador
Lubin, Dr. Simon J.
Luce, Edgar A.
Lyon, Charles
Mcadoo, William G.
Mcbride, Dr. James H.
Mccabe, Alexander
Mccarthy, P.H.
Mcclatchy, Charles K.
Mcclatchy, Valentine Stuart
Mccormick, (Joseph) Medili
Mccormick, Paul J.
Mccormick, Ruth (Mrs. Medill)
Macfarlane, Peter Clark
Mckenna, Joseph
Mclaughlin, John P.
Mcleod, George
Mcnab, John L.
Mcnabb, Samuel B.
Madsen, Martin C.
Mathewson, Walter G.
Merchants and Manufacturers Association
Merriam, Charles E.
Merritt, Ralph P.
Mexicans In California
Mexico
Minorities See--Mexicans In California, Japanese In California, and Indians, Treatment of.
Minimum Wage See--Wages--Minimum Wage.
Morehouse, Edward W.
Morgan, Anne
Morrison, Willis I.
Morrisson, Mary
Mulholland, William
Murasky, Frank J.
Muscle Shoals, Alabama
Myers, Louis W.
National Consumers League
National Municipal League
National Recovery Act
National Woman's Party
National Women's Trade Union League
New, Harry S.
Newspapers, California
Neylan, John Francis
Noel, Frances
Nolan, John I.
Obenauer, Marie L.
Older, Fremont
Opium Trade Box 12.
Orr, Mrs. James W.
Otis, Harrison Gray
Owen, Robert L.
Pan-American Treaties See--Treaties.
Pan-Pacific Women's Association
Park, Maud Wood
Paul, Alice
Peixotto, Jessica
Penrose, Boies
Perkins, Frances
Pershing, John J.
Phelan, James D.
Phipps, Lawrence C.
Pinchot, Amos
Pinchot, Cornelia B.
Pinchot, Gifford
Poindexter, Miles
Pomerene, Atlee
Porter, Stephen G.
Pound, Roscoe
Powell, Thomas Reed
Progressive Party
Prohibition
Railroad Commission, California Box 1/folders 6,10.
Reed, John
Republican Party
Requa, Mark L.
Richardson, Friend W.
Robins, Margaret Drier
Robins, Raymond
Robinson, Henry M.
Roche, Theodore J.
Rockefeller, John D., Jr.
Rodgers, William L.
Rolph, James, Jr.
Roosevelt, Franklin D.
Roosevelt, Theodore
Root, Elihu
Rowell, Chester H.
Ruef, Abe
Russia Box 2/folder 14.
Ryan, John A.
Sandford, J.B.
Save The Redwoods League
Scharrenberg, Paul
Schlesinger, Ben F.
Seibold, Louis
Seton, Ernest Thompson
Severance, Caroline M.
Sherwin, Belle
Shortridge, Samuel M.
Simons, Grace C.
Sinclair, Upton
Slattery, Harry
Smith, Alfred E.
Smith, Walter George
Smoot, Reed
Social Health Insurance
Socialism
Soule, George Henry, Jr.
Southern Pacific Railroad Box 1/folder 4,5.
Spreckels, John D.
Sproul, Robert G.
Squier, George O.
Stanfield, Robert N.
Stephens, William D.
Stimson, Marshall
Sullivan, Matt I.
Sutherland, George H.
Sutherland, Howard
Swing, Philip D.
Taft, William Howard
Tariff Box 6/folder 6.
Taxation--California
Taxpayers' Association
Tea Pot Dome Scandal Box 1/folder 14.
Telfer, Robert
Treaties
Unemployment Compensation See--Insurance, Unemployment.
U.S.--Foreign Relations
U.S. Supreme Court
Upton, Harriet Taylor
Vandegrift, Rolland A.
Van Renesselaer, Lolita
Vittum, Harriet E.
Vivisection; Medical Ideas
Von Der Nienberg, Bertha
Wadsworth Amendment, Proposed Box 1/folders 7,14-16.
Wages--Minimum Wage
Wallace, Albert J.
Walsh, Frank P.
Water Resources Development
Webb, Ulysses S.
Weeks, John Wingate
Weinstock, Harris
West, George P.
West, T.C.
Wetmore, Maude
White, William Allen
Wilbur, Curtis D.
Wilcox, Delos F.
Will, Arthur P.
Willebrandt, Mabel W.
Williams, Helen K.
Wilson, J. Stitt
Wilson, William B.
Wilson, Woodrow
Winter, Alice A.
Woman-Employment
Woman--Suffrage
Woman's Party See--National Woman's Party.
Women's Land Army
Wood, Leonard
Woodruff, Clinton R.
Woolwine, Thomas L.
Working Conditions
Works, John D.
Works, Lewis R.
World Court
World War,
Young, Clement C.
Young, Stark--Miscellaneous: Box 10.
Disarmament.; California -- Politics and government -- 1850-1950.; Labor movement -- California.; Public welfare.; Minimum wage -- Law and legislation -- California.; Women -- Suffrage.; Dairy laws -- California.; Political parties -- United States.; Edson, Katherine Philips, 1870-1933--Archives.; Johnson, Hiram, 1866-1945--Correspondence.; League of Women Voters of California
- Correspondence (1913-1932)
  General note
  Letters from Katherine Philips Edson to:
  - (1913), 16 pieces
    - Hiram Johnson., Hospital inspection, 8-hour law for student nurses, Buiberson milk bills. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chester Rowell., Hospital inspection bill, Johnson, election defeat of Shenk and Earl. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. James Orr., California State Fair, women's building. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Burke attack on Attorney Grant Jackson malicious. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hiram Johnson., Whittier Girls' School, acknowledgement of appointment to Industrial Welfare Commission, Ben F. Schlesinger, Albert Bonnheim, J.H. McBride, Frances Noel, minimum wage, Progressive Party, Willis I. Morrison, Arthur P. Will, Lewis Works, Grant Jackson (suggested for judgships), Senator John D. Works. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hiram Johnson., Acknowledgement of appointment to Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Hiram Johnson., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. James Orr., Katherine Philips Edson's speaking engagements. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Walter Mathewson., Compensation Act, Meyer Lissner. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mrs. Byron Thomas., Woman's role in the community. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - (1914), 80 pieces
    - (Telegram) Chester Rowell., Appointment to Training School Board, Whittier Girls' School, Dr. Adelaide Brown for appointment to State Board of Health. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. James Orr., Whittier Girl's School Board appointees. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., Dr. Sherwin Gibbons, unemployment situation and Mexican population in particular; Immigration Commission. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., coming election, Board of Health, Whittier Girls' School, Eshelman vs. Roberts for Lieutenant Governor. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. Byron Thomas., Women's need for ballot. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., Katherine Philips Edson's speaking engagements, Dr. Sherwin Gibbons and Health Board Appointment, Earl. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell., 8-hour law for nurses, John P. McLaughlin, Republican Party, A.B.C. Dohrmann, Progressive Party, Rowell vs. Heney in coming election. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Walter Mathewson., Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., Speaking engagements, California Federation of Women's Clubs, Mrs. James Orr, Mrs. Herbert C. Cable. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alexander McCabe., Mrs. James Orr, coming election. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., Carver and milk bills, 8-hour law petition, minimum wage petition, John P. McLaughlin, Socialist Party, Dr. Adelaide Brown, Nathan Straus, Dr. Sherwin Gibbon, Ben F. Schlesinger, George P. West. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell., Samuel Shortridge, Oscar Lawler, Theodore Bell, Mrs. Woodbridge, Earl, Heney, A.E. Boynton, Walter Mathewson, Progressive Party, Edward A. Dickson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., Milk bills and opposition, Judge Willis I. Morrison, Frances Noel, Francis Heney, Progressive Party, Edward A. Dickson, Central Labor Council, Dr. John Randolph Haynes, Tribune, election. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell., Edward A. Dickson, gubernatorial campaign, Gifford Pinchot, Francis Heney, Progressive Party, Rowell's election campaign, Meyer Lissner. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Dr. William H. Burke., Chester Rowell, Francis Heney, Riverside convention, gubernatorial campaign. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell., California Federation of Women's Clubs convention, Anne Morgan. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell., Friday Morning Club, Samuel Shortridge, Hiram Johnson, Mrs. B. Woodbridge. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Hiram Johnson., Helen Williams, Riverside convention, Clara S. Foltz, Mrs. James E. Tucker vs. Milton Schmidt in election, Mrs. Bancroft, Francis Heney, Chester Rowell, Egan case, E.J. Fleming, Senator Brown, Henry Lyon, Earl. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Chester Rowell., Edward A. Dickson, Meyer Lissner, Willis I. Morrison, Francis Heney, Hiram Johnson, Mrs. Gerberding, Marshall Stimson, Heney-Rowell primary campaigns, Miss Todd. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Russell Avery--Theodore Roosevelt., Gifford Pinchot, Heney-Rowell campaign. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Theodore Roosevelt--Russell Avery., Heney-Rowell campaign. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - To the Editor H.B.--Mrs. D.C. McCan. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Woman suffrage campaign in New York, Hiram Johnson's campaign for re-election against the political machine. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Harriet Odgers., Woman suffrage, Hiram Johnson, George Creel. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. I.A.T. Campbell., Hiram Johnson, effects of enfranchisement on California women. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Walter Mathewson., Canning industry, Industrial Welfare Commission, Butler, Paul Scharrenburg, Woman's Trade Union League, woman suffrage, proposed trip East for Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mrs. Blaney. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - (telegram) Miss MacDonald, for Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., California Federation of Labor and minimum wage resolution, A.B.C. Dohrmann, Walter Mathewson, Eastern trip. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Woman suffrage, Hiram Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alexander McCabe., E.H. Hancock, Butler, Edward A. Dickson, Henry Lyon, John Reed, Hiram Johnson's election victory. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - (1915), 40 pieces
    - Mrs. Norman Whitehouse., James Rolph, Jr., woman suffrage, women and jury duty. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., Recommendation of Myron Westover for Superior Court judgship, Anne Morgan. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Woman suffrage in California, andrew J. Gallagher, Maud Younger, California Federation of Women's Clubs. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., State Senator Brown, Brs. Cable, anti-vivisection legislation, Dr. John R. Haynes, Jones and his wife's campaign. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., Article on Industrial Welfare Commission in New Republic. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mary White., Canning industry, 8-hour law, Industrial Welfare Commission investigations and jurisdiction, hop-picking industry, State Commission on Immigration and Housing, California Federation of Women's Clubs convention. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., Industrial Welfare Commission, Minimum Wage Act, child labor bill, Father Crowley, Frederick W. Kellogg. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Hiram Johnson., San Francisco Chronicle, Campbell, Purkitt, Democratic Party, Edward A. Dickson, Dr. John R. Haynes, anti-vivisection bill, Florence Kelley. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Walter Mathewson., Marie Obenauer, canning industry, Harry Scheel, garment industry, Albert Bonnheim. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Walter Mathewson., National Civil Service Commission, Charles Wesley Reed, Albert Bonnheim, Stockton employers. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Walter Mathewson., Charles Wesley Reed, Hunter, problems with Civil Service Commission. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Walter Mathewson., Civil Service Commission, Hunter, Whitman, Charles Wesley Reed, Williams, Harry Scheel, A.B.C. Dohrmann, Industrial Welfare Commission organization. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alexander McCade., Recommendation of Zoe Dobson, Henry Lyon. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Walter Mathewson. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A.B.C. Dohrmann., Industrial Welfare Commission, Harry Scheel, Helen Bary, canning industry, merchants and wages, Dr. Boyd, safety and health in industry, Walter Mathewson, Chase, John P. McLaughlin, Marie Obenauer, Immigration and Housing Commission, Dr. Frederick C. Howe. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Editor, Atlantic City Review., Woman suffrage. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Edith M. Adamson., Woman suffrage, union open and closed shops. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - (telegram) New York Tribune., Woman suffrage. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - (1916), 60 pieces
    - Hiram Johnson., Mary Roberts Coolidge, California Civic League, Miss Whitney, representation of women on state boards, State Federation of Women's Clubs, United Republican Women's Club. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson., United Republican ticket in coming election and relation to Progressive Party, Mary S. Gibson, Shelley Tolhurst, Helen K. Williams. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chester Rowell., organization of Women's United Republican League, Guy Earl, Hiram Johnson, Dr. Adelaide Brown. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson., Hughes Alliance, Edward A. Dickson, Progressive Party, Mrs. Aylett Cotton, Theodore Roosevelt. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Marie Obenauer, Bertha von der Nienburg., Industrial Welfare Commission, canning industry, Frances A. Kellor, William D. Stephens. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anne Rhodes., Chester Rowell, William Crocker, Nicholas Murray Butler, Francis Keesling, Charles Evans Hughes, Hiram Johnson, Harold L. Ickes' appointment in Illinois and national elections, relations between Progressives and Republicans, Judge Bordwell, Wilcox. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Harriet Vittum., Charles Evans Hughes, Garfield, Hiram Johnson, Mary S. Gibson, Hughes Alliance, Woodrow Wilson, Women's Party, woman suffrage, Republicans and Progressives. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chester Rowell., Hiram Johnson, Hughes Train, Congressional Union. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hiram Johnson., Johnson's attitude towards California women, Walt Whitman. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Miss George., Mary S. Gibson, election work, Mrs. Bentley, Mrs. Krebs, Mary R. Coolidge. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anne Rhodes., National campaign, Chester Rowell, Hiram Johnson, Charles Evans Hughes, Mary S. Gibson, Republican Executive Committee, Mrs. Krebs, James Garfield, child labor bill, Woodrow Wilson, Hughes Train. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Mary S. Gibson., James Garfield, women's movement in election, Harold Ickes, Wilson administration, Charles Evans Hughes, Ben F. Schlesinger, A.B.C. Dohrmann, Frances Kellor, Hughes Train, woman suffrage, Inez M. Boissevain, Samuel. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Clara S. Foltz., 5th Anniversary Suffrage Luncheon, Patton, Hiram Johnson. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Chester Rowell., Hughes Train, Masters, Woodrow Wilson, Mrs. O'Shaughnessy. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Grace Simons., Legislative Council, Miss Ogden, Lucia Dunham, election. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Meyer Lissner., Hiram Johnson and Harrison Gray Otis' talk, Earl papers, William D. Stephens, Edward A. Dickson, Alexander McCabe, Gavin Craig, Francis Heney, James Rolph, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Grace Simons., Hiram Johnson and Harrison G. Otis' talk, Charles Evans Hughes, Woodrow Wilson, Chester Rowell, Republican National Committee, Democratic Party, Harry Chandler, Francis Heney, Frances Noel. (Box 1, Folder 4)